MICHAEL J. GROSS

(203) 848-4651 mjgross@protonmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/mjg1982 Midvale, UT 84047 https://github.com/mjgross82 https://github.com/mjgross82

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with an academic background in social science research and a professional background in retail management. Leveraging a newfound aptitude for clean and concise JavaScript and CSS to deliver functional, responsive websites. Methodical, test-driven developer with a penchant for object-oriented programming. Poised to provide unique insight into consumer interactions with emerging technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Materialize, Bulma, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, MySQL,

ReactJS, Express.js, Handlebars.js, MongoDB

Applications: Visual Studio Code, GitHub, Heroku, Postman, STATA, SPSS, Sublime Text, GitKraken

PROJECTS

8-Bit Bartender | https://github.com/Eelektrick/8-bit-bartender | https://eelektrick.github.io/8-bit-bartender/

- A retro-themed guide to cocktail recipes. The user inputs the name of a beverage and is presented with a list of ingredients and their nutritional information
- Lead front-end developer, wrote HTML and CSS, project management and GitHub version control
- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, and APIs

Roster Generator | https://github.com/mjgross82/team_roster_generator

- A Command Line Interface application written in Node.js that asks the user a series of questions to dynamically create an HTML file that displays a summary of information for each member of a team
- Wrote and passed a total of 17 tests over 4 test suites during development with an emphasis on ES6 syntax and object-oriented programming
- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js

EXPERIENCE

eCommerce Department Manager, Walmart, South Jordan, UT (February 2019 - June 2020)

- Led a team of approximately 30 associates through a transformative recalibration around best practices and standards, resulting in significant improvement in numerous metrics
- Drove a roughly 60% increase in daily order volume to a maximum of over 300 orders and up to \$35,000 in sales
- Achieved customer satisfaction scores of over 90% with upwards of 10% market penetration for over three consecutive months
- Collaborated with storewide management team to increase general merchandise and online grocery order fill rates

Assistant Store Manager, Starbucks, Eugene, OR (September 2015 - May 2017)

- Supervised daily operations of multiple stores, each generating over \$1.5 million annually, in the absence of their respective store managers
- Initiated a food sales drive resulting in 8% growth over previous year food sales to over 38 UPH
- Recruited and trained high-performing employees for barista and shift supervisor roles in response to staffing needs based on monthly labor availability assessments
- Maintained turnover of roughly 5% below target through effective applicant screening measures, constructive feedback, ongoing development conversations, and promotion of benefits utilization
- Monitored daily sales and adjusted scheduling as needed to meet a goal of +/- 3% labor efficiency

Shift Supervisor, Starbucks, Hamden, CT and Eugene, OR (Jan 2007 - September 2015)

- Analyzed weekly and daily food sales data and adjusted inventory pars, reducing food waste to less than 7% of sales
- Executed operational standards while directing a team of up to 10 partners per shift to efficiently manage customer traffic
- Communicated indicators of customer satisfaction while modeling and coaching positive customer oriented behaviors
- Conducted ongoing systematic training of employees in accordance with company-wide, behavior based training protocols

Behavior Therapist, The Institute of Professional Practice, Meriden, CT (August 2011 - June 2012)

- Implemented academic, behavioral, and social interventions for children and adolescents with problem behaviors across multiple school settings
- Assessed intervention efficacy based on observed trends in behavioral data and suggested modifications as needed
- Maintained precise tables and charts of daily program data using Microsoft Excel
- Cooperated with an interdisciplinary team of education professionals to promote plan adherence

EDUCATION

Certificate: Full Stack Web Development, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

A 26 week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS

Bachelor of Science: Psychology, Southern Connecticut State University, New Haven, CT

Research Specialization including the following coursework: Statistics in Psychology, Experimental Methods, Data Gathering Techniques: Assessment, Data Gathering Techniques: Instrumentation, Methods of Social Research, Quantitative Data Analysis, Programming in BASIC, Writing for Business and Industry, Elementary Statistics